Damn! When are we going to eat, Cromwell?
真该死 我们什么时候能开餐 克伦威尔
I'm famished!
我要饿晕了
Swim hat?
小泳帽吗
Very pretty, isn't it?
特别漂亮是不是
It's just come from the embroiderer.
这是刺绣工匠刚呈上的
Isn't it sweet?
是不是很可爱
For her little head.
戴在她的小脑袋上
Cremuel?
克伦威尔
I am told that when you thought the King was dead,
我听说 当你以为国王驾崩时
your first action was to send for the bastard Mary.
你的第一反应竟然是传召那个私生女玛丽
You did not think of me,
你竟然没有考虑过我
or my daughter
和我的女儿
or the child I was carrying then.
和我当时身上怀着的宝宝
I cannot hold the throne for an infant in the cradle.
我不能把王位交给一个尚在襁褓中的婴儿
I cannot hold the throne for an unborn baby.
更不能交给一个尚未出世的孩子
I promoted you.
是我提拔的你
I am responsible for your rise.
我是你地位提升如此之快的因素
And at the first opportunity, you have betrayed me.
可一旦出现了机会 你却背叛了我
Madam, nothing here is personal.
夫人 我做的事都不是出于私心的
You think you've grown great.
你觉得你已羽翼丰满
You think you no longer need me,
不再需要我的庇护
but you've forgotten the most important thing.
但你却忘记了最为重要的一件事
Cremuel!
克伦威尔
Those who've been made can be unmade.
所有的事情都可以推倒重来
I entirely agree.
我不能同意更多
We want the concubine ousted.
我们想驱逐那个姘妇
We know you want it too.
我们知道你也很想这样
We?
"我们" 指的是
My friends in this matter are very near the throne,
我有些很觊觎 也与王位有血缘关系的朋友们
those in the line of old King Edward.
爱德华国王一脉的家族
Lord Exeter, the Courtenay family.
比如埃克塞特大人 考特尼家族
Lord Montague, his brother, Geoffrey Pole, Lady Margaret Pole.
蒙塔古大人 他的哥哥 杰弗里・波利  玛格丽特・波利夫人
These are the principal persons on whose behalf I speak.
这些都是我交谈过的最有分量的人了
But, as you will be aware,
我还给你提个醒
the most part of England would rejoice to see the King free of her.
大部分英国民众都会很高兴国王罢黜她
I don't think the most part of England knows or cares.
我可不认为大部分英国子民会知道或在意这事
What do you require of me?
那你们到底需要我做什么
We...require...that you join us.
我们...需要...你加入我们
We're content to have Seymour's girl crowned.
我们想要把西摩家的女儿推上王后之位
She's known to favour true religion
她因热爱真实的宗教信仰而闻名
and we believe she will bring Henry back to Rome.
而我们也相信她能让亨利与罗马教廷重归于好
And this is our difficulty, Cromwell.
但这也正是我们的难处 克伦威尔
We know you are a Lutheran.
我们知道 你是个路德会教友
Me? No, sir. I'm a banker.
什么 我不是 先生 我只是个银行主
What will happen to Anne Boleyn?
那你们会怎么处理安妮・博林
I don't know.
我不知道
Convent?
可能遣送到康文特去吧
Look at this little doggie.
看这个小可怜哦
Oh, why are you so sad, Mark?
噢 你为什么看上去这么悲伤 马克
You have no business being sad.
你根本勿须忧伤
You're here to entertain us.
你在这里是为了愉悦我们的
Oh, for heaven's sake, stand on your feet.
噢 我的天 你给我站好了
I do you favour by noticing you at all.
我给你面子才看你一眼
What do you expect?
你还指望什么
Do you think I should talk to you as if you were a gentleman?
你觉得我应该像和绅士一般说话的和你说话吗
But I can't do that, Mark. You see...
但我做不到 马克 你看
because you're an inferior person.
因为你本身就是个下等人
No, madam.
是的 王后
I don't expect a word.
我什么都没有指望的
A look suffices me.
您看我一眼 已能使我满足
Well?
是吗
Aren't you going to praise my eyes now?
那你现在是不是要开始赞颂我的眼睛了
Why do you encourage that boy?
你为什么要鼓励那个男孩
All manner of puppy dogs are encouraged here.
所有有礼貌的宠物都该得到鼓励的
Some are coming in AND out of season.
有些时候进来的不合时宜
Are you referring to me, Norris?
你是在引用我的话吗 诺里斯
I could happily give this puppy dog a kick in his ribs
要是能一脚踢一下那"宠物"的肚腩 真是要乐死了
- that he won't forget.  - No kicking in my chamber, if you please.
- 他就永远不会忘了  - 不许在我的宫殿内随便踢 拜托
He gets himself agitated
他把自己弄得这么焦虑
because he thinks I come here to cast my fancy at Lady Mary.
因为他总觉得我到这里来是想勾搭玛丽夫人的
We all know he hopes to marry her himself.
我们都知道其实是他自己想娶玛丽夫人
But really I come here for the sake of another.
但说真的 我到这来 是为了另一个女人的
- And do you know who that is?  - No, tell me.
- 你知道我是为谁来吗  - 不知道 你告诉我吧
I can't guess.
我猜不到
Is it Lady Rochford here?
难道是罗奇福德夫人吗
Surely not one so old?
肯定不会是年龄这么大的吧
No. It is yourself, Madam.
是您 王后
Perhaps you should kick him, Gentle Norris,
诺里斯 或许你该踹他一脚
for the honour of the Queen of England.
以维护英格兰王后的尊严
Ah! Here's the man for me.
来了个我的亲信
Will Brereton is one who shoots his arrow straight.
这位威尔・布里尔顿能把弓箭笔直的射出去
What's to do here?
你们在干嘛呢
Everyone's been fighting, and all because of that boy Mark.
每个人都在争吵 起源于那个叫马克的男孩
I think he should be dropped from a great height.
我觉得他应该从高空扔下去
Just like your dog, Purkoy.
就像你的那条小狗 博克尔
Do that again and I will hit you back.
你再扇一次 我就会还手了
You're no queen. You're just a knight's daughter
你不是王后 你不过是个骑士的女儿
and your time has come.
而且你大限将至了
Harry?
哈里
Do me a good turn - take away my brother's wife and drown her.
帮我个忙 把我的这位弟妹带走 然后将她溺死
- Anne!  - What?
- 安妮  - 干嘛
Didn't you swear you'd walk barefoot to China for me?
你不是曾发誓说 愿意为我赤脚走路到中国去的吗
I think it was barefoot to Walsingham I offered.
我记得我说的是赤脚走到沃尔辛厄姆
Perhaps you can repent your sins there.
那或许你能在那边忏悔你的罪孽
Because if anything happened to the King, you'd look to have me.
因为如何国王有任何不测 你会想尽办法得到我的
Oh, yes, you see now, Mary, why he hasn't married you yet?
噢 不好意思了 玛丽 你知道他为什么一直不娶你吗
It's because he's in love with me. Or so he claims.
因为他一直爱的都是我 据他所说是这样的
And yet he won't prove it by putting Lady Rochford in a sack
而现在 他也不愿把罗奇福德夫人装进袋子里 扔到河里面
and dropping her in the river.
来证明对我的爱了
Will you spill all your secrets, Anne, or only some?
那你愿意分享你的全部秘密吗 安妮 还是只有一部分
Oh, he... Get him back.
把他...把他叫回来
It was idle talk. Get him back.
我刚刚是气话 快把他叫回来
Get him back and he'll swear on the Bible.
让他回来 他会对着圣经起誓
He knows me to be a good wife.
他知道我会是一个好妻子的
Get him back! Harry!
快让他回来 哈里
Henry had heard about the fight with Norris.
亨利听说了她和诺里斯之间的争吵
We could all see from the courtyard.
我们从庭院里都看到了
She had her hands...
她把她的手...
You know the King's great tapestry?
你知道国王最爱的织锦的
Where the Queen clasps her hands together?
王后将它一起握在手上
He didn't look persuaded.
但国王显然没有被说服
Did you not go to her to comfort her?
你没有去劝慰一下她吗
She being your mistress?
她毕竟是你的女主人
No. I came looking for you.
没有 我直接来找你商讨了
Before they were married,
在他们结婚之前
Anne used to practise with Henry.
安妮曾与亨利练习过
In the French fashion.
做一些新奇的玩法
You know what I mean.
你知道我什么意思的
Lady Rochford, I have no idea what you mean.
罗奇福德夫人 我不知道你的意思
Oh, you think you can shame me out of saying what I must say?
噢 你以为我会羞耻的不好意思说出我的意思来吗
I'm no virgin girl.
我可不是一个处女
She induced him to put his seed otherwise than he should have.
她勾引他把他的精子 射到了个不正常的地方
Now Henry calls it a filthy proceeding.
现在亨利称之为一个肮脏的口
But God love him, he doesn't know where the filth begins.
但上帝还是爱他 他不知道那里一开始装的什么
My husband George...
我的丈夫乔治...
..is always with Anne.
..总是和安妮混在一起
He's her brother. It's natural.
他是她弟弟 这很正常
There's nothing natural in George.
但乔治没有正常的一面
And nothing is forbidden.
在他眼里 没有什么是不可以做的
I've seen them kiss.
我曾见过他们接吻
Brothers may kiss their sis...
弟弟亲吻姐姐没什么...
His tongue in her mouth. Hers in his.
他的舌头在她的嘴里 她的舌头也在他嘴里
You want me to record that?
你想让我将这件事记录在案吗
If you're worried you won't remember it.
如果你害怕 这件事你不会记住的
Why would she do such a thing?
可她为什么要做出这样的事
You know why. The better to rule.
你知道为什么的 为了更好地统治
Suppose she gets a boy and it has Weston's long face?
假如她生下了一个男孩 却而且有着威斯顿的长脸
Or looks like Will Brereton?
或者看着像威尔・布里尔顿
But they can't call it a bastard if it looks like a Boleyn.
但如果长得像博林家的孩子 就没理由说他是私生子了
Be advised by me.
我衷心建议你
Speak to no-one.
千万别告诉任何人
Speak to Mark Smeaton.
去和马克・斯米顿谈谈吧
We can leave that here, Mark.
我们可以把那个留在这 马克
I thought there was to be a great company?
我还以为会有一帮人呢
I thought I was going to entertain you.
我以为我是负责来愉悦你的
Make no doubt of it.
毫无疑问
You see, Mark,
你看 马克
my master, the King, and my mistress, the Queen,
我的主人 国王 和我的女主人 王后
are at odds.
发生了分歧
Everyone knows.
每个人都知道
And my dearest wish is to reconcile them.
而我最大的心愿就是他们能够和好
The word at court is you're keeping company with the Queen's enemies.
可你在议会上说的话 就好像是你在与王后的敌人为伍
How else am I to find out their practices?
那不然我怎能察觉出他们的动机图谋
Ah. If only I could believe that.
信你才怪
I don't blame you, Mark.
我不怪你 马克
There's such ill-feeling at the court, no-one trusts anyone.
在议会上这种恶心的地方 人与人无信任可言
But I've come to you because you're close to the Queen,
但是我找你来 是因为你和王后的关系密切
and I'd really love to know why she's so unhappy
我也真的很想知道 她为什么如此不高兴
and if there's anything that I can do to remedy it.
有什么事我能做的
It's no wonder she's unhappy.
难怪她不开心
She's in love.
她正在热恋中
With whom?
和谁
With me.
和我
You're amazed.
你看起来很吃惊
I'm...
我...
I'm not as amazed as you might think.
我没有你想象的那么吃惊
I've seen how she looks at you.
我知道她是怎么看你的
And it's no surprise that any woman would be drawn to you.
这不奇怪 任何女人都会被你吸引的
You're a very handsome young man.
你是一个非常英俊的年轻小伙
But we thought you were a sodomite.
但是我们觉得你是个娈童
Rich!
里奇
I'm as good a man as any of them.
我是和他们一样的男人
Of course you are and the Queen would give you good report.
当然 相信王后也会给你一个很好的地位
She's tried you. Found you to her liking.
她审视过你 发现你很对她的胃口
I can't discuss it.
我不想讨论这个
No, no, you mustn't. But we can assume.
不 不 你可以不讨论 但我们可以假设
She's not an inexperienced woman.
她不是一个没有经验的女人
I think she would not be interested in anything less than a masterly performance.
我想她不会对一个经验少 表现拙劣的人感兴趣的
Well, I will say this -
好吧 我会说
we men born poor
我们出身贫寒的人
are in no wise inferior in that way.
还做出那样卑贱的行为是不明智的
How true.
很正确
Though the noble gentlemen like to keep that secret from the ladies.
尽管贵族的绅士们 喜欢对女士们的保留秘密
They wouldn't want the competition, would they?
他们不想要竞争 对吧
If you mean she has other lovers, I wouldn't know.
如果你的意思是她是否有别的情人 这我不知道
I haven't asked her.
我没有问过她
- But they're jealous of me. - Are they?
- 但是他们都嫉妒我   - 是吗?
- Weston and Norris, those lords.
- 威斯顿和诺里斯 这些大人们
They call me boy, but they're jealous.
他们叫我小男孩 但我知道他们是嫉妒我
Well, perhaps she tried them and they were a disappointment.
好吧 也许她也试探了他们 而他们却令人失望了
And you take the prize.
你则是赢家
How often?
多久一次
You've given us two names, Mark.
你已经给我们两个名字了 马克
Now name the others.
现在说出其他人的名字吧
And answer Master Richard. How often?
然后回答理查德学士 多久一次
Perhaps you're wise not to speak.
嗯 也许你不说话是明智的
Best to have it all written down.
最好把名单都写下来
The council will hardly believe it otherwise.
否则议会很难相信它的真实性
They'll be amazed at your success. Jealous.
他们会为你的成功感到惊讶 甚至嫉妒
"Smeaton, what is your secret?" they'll demand.
他们会问 "斯米顿 你的秘密是什么"
And you'll answer, "Ah, I can't impart."
你会回答 "啊 我不能透露"
But you will impart, Mark.
但是你终要说的 马克
You'll do it freely.
你会自愿说出来
Or you'll do it enforced.
或者被迫说
Seat yourself, pretty boy.
坐下吧 俊俏的小男孩
I take it back. I can't give you any names.
我收回我的话 我不会告诉你任何名字的
I don't know how I came to say what I did.
我不知道我怎么会到这来 说我做了什么
No, nor do I. No-one hurt you or coerced you. You spoke freely.
不 我也是 没有人伤害你或强迫你的 你可以畅所欲言
These two gentlemen are my witnesses.
这两位先生是我的证人
I take it back.
我收回我说的话
I don't think so.
我可不这么认为
Tell us about your adultery with the Queen
告诉我们 你和王后通奸
and what you know about her dealings with the other gentlemen
还有你所知道的她和其他男人的来往
and IF your confession is true and full,
如果你的供述是真实完整的
perhaps the King will show you mercy.
说不定国王会怜悯你 饶你一命
Would you like to spend ten minutes alone with Master Richard here?
你愿意和理查德学士在这 独处十分钟吗
Five would do it.
五分钟就行了
He will write down what you say, Mark.
他会如实写下你所说的 马克
But he won't necessarily write down what we do.
但他不一定会写下我们所对你做的
Oh, God!
噢 天啊
Do you follow me?
你听懂了吗
Mother Mary, help me.
圣母玛利亚 救救我
I can't tell you what I don't know.
我不能告诉你们 我并不知道的事啊
Can't you?
你不能吗
No.
不能
Well, then you'll have to be my guest for the night, Mark.
好吧 那看来你是我们今晚留宿的客人了 马克
Oh! Please.
噢 求求你了
Well, there aren't many men alive
好吧 他们中没有多少人还活着了
who can say they took me by surprise.
他们还真是吓了我一跳
Years of being despised by lords has made a boaster of him.
常年被贵族们渲染 已经让他变得大言不惭
Sometimes I think I should have taken him in here.
有时候我觉得我应该带他来这里
I don't want him hurt.
我不想伤害他
If we have to torture sad creatures like that, what next?
如果我们必须要像折磨可怜的生物那样 接下来怎么做
Stamping on dormice?
踩踏睡鼠
Tell Wriothesley to come tomorrow.
让里奥谢思利明天过来
What is this?
这是什么
It's where the phantom lives.
这是幽灵住的地方
In you go.
进去吧
Please!
拜托
Let me out! Please let me out!
让我出去 请让我出去吧
Let me out!
让我出去啊
Henry Norris, Francis Weston.
有哈里・诺里斯和佛朗西斯・威斯顿
And William Brereton and Francis Bryan.
以及威廉・布里尔顿和佛朗西斯・布莱恩
Richard Long, Walter Walsh.
理查德・朗 沃尔特・沃尔什
You had to do with the Queen - how many times?
你和王后 到底有过多少次苟且之事
A thousand? Three or four.
得有上千次了 三四次而已
Three or four.
三四次而已
Richard.
理查德
Go to the King at Greenwich.
去格林威治觐见国王
He'll be expecting you.
他在等着见你
Trust your message to no-one.
千万不要相信任何一个人
Put the word in his ear yourself
要亲自把消息送入他耳里
Page!
佩奇
Tell Henry Norris to retire from the field.
让哈里・诺里斯从丛林里回来
Ride with me, Harry.
哈里 和我一起骑段路
Where to, my lord?
去哪里 陛下
Let's talk, you and I.
就我们俩 随便聊聊
Cromwell!
克伦威尔
I hear the singer sang to your tune.
我听说玩音乐的小子最后都几乎按照你的调子在唱歌了
What did you do to him?
你对他做了什么啊
There's a pretty ballad for you.
我有个歌谣要说给你听
The King fingers his lute, while his lutenist fingers his wife.
国王在弹琴的时候 他的琴师却在"弹"着王后
You have the warrant, my lord?
你带搜查令了吗 大人
Perhaps this'll teach Henry to listen to me.
或许这样能教育亨利多听听我的
Uncle.
叔父
Lord Chancellor.
大法官阁下
Master Treasurer.
财政大臣阁下
And Cremuel.
还有克伦威尔
The man I created.
我亲手栽培出来的男人
He created you in turn, madam.
不 夫人 是他亲手扶植你上位的
And be sure he repents of it.
我确信他自己也在懊悔的
Oh, but I was sorry first.
但是我先感到遗憾的
And I am sorry more.
也遗憾的更多
Ready to go?
准备好出发了吗
I don't know how to be ready.
我不知该如何准备
Just come with us.
只要跟我们走就好
I'm to blame.
都怪我
I suspected her and did nothing.
我怀疑了她 却无计可施
I...
我...
I never had a better opinion in a woman than I had in her.
我从未对一个女人 有像对她那样的好印象
I can't believe she's guilty.
我至今仍不敢相信她有罪
Except I know Your Highness would never go so far if she weren't.
只是我知道如果她无罪的话 国王陛下是不会这么做的
She deceived all of us.
她欺骗了我们所有人
When I look back, it all falls into place.
我现在回想起来 也都想明白了
So many friends lost,
失去了那么多的朋友
alienated...
渐行渐远...
Worse.
很是糟心
When I think of Wolsey...
每当我想起沃尔西的时候...
The way she practised against him.
想起了安妮与他作对的样子
She said she loved me.
她说她是爱我的
But she meant the opposite.
但是其实她一点也不爱我
I've written a play.
我写过一个剧本
A tragedy.
是一个悲剧
My own story.
我自己的故事
You should keep it sir, till we have more leisure to do it justice.
您先留着吧 陛下 等我们有足够的闲暇时间来品鉴它
But I want you to see her true nature.
但我想要让你们看看她的本性
I believe she has committed adultery with 100 men.
我相信她已经与上百个男人通奸过了
But her brother?
但和她的弟弟
Is it likely?
真的有可能吗
Well, I doubt she could resist!
我还不相信她能抵挡诱惑
Why spare?
为何要宽恕呢
Why not drink the cup to its filthy dregs?
明知是破鞋 为何还要穿
Come, Wolsey, we're fetching you to Hell,
来吧 沃尔西 我们领你到地狱来
where our master, Beelzebub, is expecting you to supper!
我们的主人 别西卜圣经中的鬼王] 正等着你共进晚餐呢
Beelzebub would have you joint his venison.
别西卜愿意与你共享鹿肉
He's heard of your skill as a butcher!
他听说你擅长屠杀
I know why I'm here.
我知道为什么我在这里
My wife.
因为我的妻子
What has she said?
她说了什么
Whatever it is, you can't hold me on the word of one woman.
不管说了什么 你都不能因为一个女人的一面之词而抓我
There've been other women who have been recipients
也有其他女人说起了
of your...gallantry, George.
你的风流往事 乔治
You've always regarded women as disposable...
你一直就觉得女人是可以玩玩就扔的...
What?
怎么
You're going to put me on trial for gallantry?
你要因为我的风流韵事而审讯我吗
I didn't know it was a crime to spend time with a willing lover.
不曾想与一个自愿和我共赴巫山的情人在一起 居然是犯罪
It is when that lover is your sister.
如果那个女人是你的亲姐姐时 那就是犯罪了
My family has served the King of England for generations.
我的家族世世代代为英国国王效劳
I have been at the side of Henry since I was a boy.
我自小就在亨利的左右服侍了
I love him like a brother. I would never forget my honour, never...
我爱他就像爱自己的兄弟一样 我从未忘记过我的荣幸...
Do you want me to write it on the wall for you, Norris?
还需要我把事情挑明了吗 诺里斯
She can't give him a son.
她不能给他生下个子嗣
He wants another wife.
他要再娶一个妻子
She won't go quietly.
她不会就这样保持沉默的
Is that simple enough for your simple tastes?
这样对你来说够简单明了吧
She has to be PUSHED. I have to PUSH her.
她需要别人给她施压 我必须要给她压力
Well, you'll get no confession from me,
好吧 反正我是不会认罪的
or Brereton either.
布里尔顿也不会的
You'll not torture gentlemen.
你不会对一位绅士用刑的
The King wouldn't permit it.
国王是不会同意的
There don't have to be formal arrangements.
那我们可以私底下来做点安排
I can put my thumbs in your eyes
我能把我的大拇指插进你的眼中
and then you would sing Green Grows The Holly...
然后你会唱 "冬青树郁郁又葱葱"...
if I asked you to.
我叫你做什么 你就做什么
Hmm?
懂了吗
Let's go back.
我们再重新谈过
I remember in the late Cardinal's time,
我记得在红衣主教大人末年
one of your household killed a man in a bowls match.
你的一个家人在弓箭比赛上杀了一个人
Well, the game can get very heated.
你知道刀剑不长眼
The Cardinal thought it was time for a reckoning,
红衣主教觉得是时候算算账了
but your family impeded the investigation
但是你的家人在调查过程中故意阻挠
and I ask myself, "Has anything changed since then?"
我就问自己 "打那之后有什么变化吗"
John ap Eyton had a quarrel with one of your household only recently.
约翰艾顿在最近和你的一个王室成员有过争执
So, that's why I'm here.
所以 这就是我在此的原因吧
Not entirely, but leave aside your adultery with the Queen,
不全是 但暂且不提你和王后通奸的事
let's concentrate on Eyton.
我们先专注于伊顿
Blows were exchanged, a man was killed.
他在与人互相射箭中 误杀了对方
Eyton was tried and acquitted.
伊顿经过审讯被无罪释放了
But you, because you have no respect for the law or...
但是你 因为你对法律的不敬...
- I have every respect! - Don't interrupt me!
- 我充分的尊重法律   - 不许打断我
You had the man abducted and hanged.
你绑架了那个人并绞死了他
You think because it's only one man, it doesn't matter.
你以为仅仅只是一个人 无关紧要是吗
You think no-one will remember, but I remember.
你以为没有人会记得住 可我记得
You think you can do anything because Norfolk favours you...
你以为有诺尔福克罩着你 你就能为所欲为了吗
The King favours me!
是国王罩着我的
Does he? Does he?
是吗 他是罩着你的吗
Well, you should complain about your lodgings, then, shouldn't you?
那你或许能和国王去抱怨一下你的居住环境 对吧
But then, Francis Bryan has been explaining it to me...
不过后来 佛朗西斯・布莱恩向我解释了
Bryan?
布莱恩
- Bryan is an enemy of mine. - And I begin to see it.
- 布莱恩可是我的敌人  - 我也意识到了
How a man may hardly know his sister.
你怎么会对你姐姐有所了解呢
She grows up in France.
毕竟她在法国长大
They meet as adults, she is like him, yet not.
成年后才相见 但她很像他
She is familiar,
她很熟知他
and yet, she piques his interest.
然后 她激起了他的兴趣
One day, his brotherly embrace lasts a little longer than usual.
直到有一天 弟弟的拥抱 比寻常持续的时间更久
The business proceeds from there.
从那时起 不正当关系便发生了
Perhaps neither of you felt you were doing anything wrong.
或许你们俩从没觉得自己做错任何事
Until some frontier was crossed.
直到突破了底线
I refuse to answer this.
我拒绝回答这个问题
Did it begin before her marriage to the King, or afterwards?
你们的关系是开始在她与国王的婚礼之前 还是之后
Brother George, that must have been a surprise.
乔治兄弟 你一定很惊诧
Rivalry from that quarter.
对立由此而生
But the morality of you gentlemen astonishes me.
但是你的绅士品格还是让我惊异
I have no opinion of George.
我对乔治没有任何意见
No opinion of incest?
对近亲通奸也没有意见吗
You take it so quietly I'm forced to think it must be true...
你说得如此平淡 我想这一定是真的了
If I said it was, you'd only accuse me of trying
如果我说是 你就会指责我
to divert attention away from myself.
在转移你对我的注意力
You've known me too long, Harry.
哈里 你真是太了解我了
Oh, I've studied you.
我曾研究过你
Studied Wolsey before you.
也还研究过沃尔西
That was politic of you. Such a great servant of the state!
你曾多么的谨慎 一个国家的忠实仆从
And such a great traitor at the end.
到最后又成了个伟大的叛徒
I remember a certain entertainment at court, do you remember?
我还记着在法庭上很有趣的一幕 你还记得吗
A play, in which the late Cardinal was set upon by demons
一场表演秀 红衣主教被恶魔们打倒
and dragged down to hell.
被扯到地狱里去了
That's why?
你就是因为这个记恨我吗
It...
它是
It was a play!
那只是一个表演秀而已
It was a joke! You can't...
只是一个玩笑 你不能...
- You can't seriously... - Life pays you out.
- 你不能当真...  - 你要用一生来偿还
Don't you find?
你没这觉悟吗
But Mark Smeaton?
那马克・斯米顿呢
- What has he done to you? - I don't know...
- 他对你做了什么  - 不知道
I just don't like the way he looks at me.
我就是不喜欢他看我的眼神
I need guilty men, Harry.
哈里 我需要有罪的人
So, I've found men who ARE guilty.
所以我就尽可能的去寻找有罪之人
Though not necessarily as charged.
虽然他们的罪 还不至于被判刑
Good morning.
早上好
I'm not long married.
我刚刚结婚
I don't know if you know that. I have a son...
你可能不知道 我还有个儿子
You have debts. To the tune of a thousand pounds.
你有债务在身 高达一千英镑
Why the devil bring that up...?
那个魔头为什么要提到这件事
No-one expects a young gallant like yourself to be thrifty,
没有人奢求像你一样挥霍无度的年轻人 能够勤俭持家
but these debts are more than you could reasonably pay.
可是你的债务 远超出你的偿还能力了
So, your own extravagance gives people to think,
所以你的放纵挥霍的行为 让人们不由得去想
what expectations did young Weston have?
这个年轻的威斯顿到底存着怎样的心思
We know the Queen gave you money.
我们都清楚王后给了你不少钱
A thousand pounds is nothing to you if you hoped to marry her
如果你能娶了她 一千英磅对你来说根本就不算什么了
after you'd contrived the King's death.
所以你谋划了国王的谋杀
I see how it'll weigh, when it's given in evidence.
当证据呈出时 我才知道了事情的严重性
I've undone myself.
我悔过自新了
I don't blame you, Cromwell.
克伦威尔 我不怪你
It's just...
只是...
..I thought I had another 20 years.
...我以为还能再活二十年的
Well, we know not the hour, do we, Francis?
佛朗西斯 我们都知道 你活不过二十小时了
Are you finished?
你搞定了吗
Has he denounced the others?
他有告发其他人吗
Do you want us to make him?
你想让我们来逼他说吗
What? What, do you think I'm too soft on young men?!
怎么 你认为我对年轻人太温柔了吗
- Do you want us to draw up charges? - Yeah, the more the merrier.
- 那你想让我们起草起诉书吗? - 嗯 罪状越多越好
Forgive me, I have to piss.
请见谅 我要去方便一下
Traitor!
叛徒
My wife is with her.
我夫人在陪着她
And her aunt, Lady Shelton.
还有她的姨母 谢尔顿夫人
How is she?
她怎么样了
Sometimes crying, sometimes laughing.
一会儿哭 一会儿笑
There's something she said.
还在自言自语什么
I only mention it because you told me to report everything I heard.
我提起这个 只是因为你下令 要报告我所听到的一切事情而已
Go on.
继续
When I told her she would stay in the same room
当我告诉她 她要住在
she had before her coronation,
加冕之前 居住的房子里
she said, "It's too good for me.
她说 "你们对我太好了
Jesus have mercy on me."
耶稣也是在怜悯我"
If she's not worthy, it's because she's guilty.
如果她不值得这一切 因为她有戴罪之人
But what is it she's done?
但是她到底做了什么
Is it something we haven't even imagined yet?'
是我们根本难以想象的吗
Would you like your furs brought in?
你喜欢那件带来的毛皮衣服吗
The ermine.
是貂皮的
And I don't want these women. I want my own women.
还有我不想看到这群女人 我想要回我的侍女们
Lady Kingston is...
金斯顿夫人是
Your spy.
你的间谍
..your hostess.
...是女主人
Am I a guest, then?
那我就是个客人了吗
Am I free to go?
那我能离开吗
I didn't think you'd object to your own aunt.
你不该违抗你的姨母的
She has a grudge against me. All I hear is tutting.
她对我满怀怨恨 满耳朵都是她的抱怨声
Do you expect applause?
那你难道还期望有掌声吗
You won't speak to me that way to me after I'm released.
等我被释放了 你就不敢冲我这样说话了
I don't know why the King is holding me here.
我不清楚国王为什么要把我软禁在这
I suppose it's some sort of test, isn't it?
我想这应该是某种考验吧
I want to see my brother.
我想见我的弟弟
That's a foolish demand in the circumstances.
在这种情况之下 真是一个愚蠢的要求
- My father. - Don't expect help there.
- 那要见我父亲 - 不要期望有人会帮你
Thomas Boleyn looks after himself first and last.
托马斯・博林会一直照看着他
I should know, he's my brother.
我知道 因为他是我的哥哥
Help the King.
别为难国王了
Unless he's merciful, there's nothing you can do for yourself.
除非他仁慈至极 否则你根本无能为力
But you can do something for your daughter.
不过你应当为你的女儿做些事
For Elizabeth.
为伊丽莎白做点事
The more penitent you show yourself through this whole process...
在整个过程当中 你表现得越悔恨...
The "process"?
什么"过程"
And what is this process to be?
这个"过程"的最终结果是什么
The confessions of the gentlemen are now being compiled.
那个先生的认罪书 已经开始在编写中了
What?
你说什么
You heard him.
你听到他说的了
They'll not lie for you.
他们是不会袒护你的
The gentlemen are to be tried together.
那几位先生将会被集体审讯
You and your brother, being ennobled,
您和您的弟弟 身为贵族
are to be judged by your peers.
将由贵族们一起审判
You have no witnesses.
你没有证人
When you were at liberty, madam,
当您身处王后之位时 夫人
your ladies were intimidated by you, forced to lie for you.
您的侍女们受你胁迫 被迫撒谎
- Now, they are emboldened...- Oh, I'm sure they are.
- 但现在她们无需再顾及... - 噢 我想也是
The way Seymour's emboldened.
就像西摩那样
Tell her from me, God sees her tricks.
替我转告她 上帝能够直视她的肮脏伎俩
No!
等等
Just tell me... You don't believe these stories against me, do you?
告诉我...你不相信那些污蔑我的故事的 对吗
I know in your heart you don't.
我知道你内心深处是不愿相信的
Do you, Cremuel?
对吗 克伦威尔
I only have a little neck.
我的脖子很脆弱
So, it'll be the work of a moment.
折断它非常容易
You said, when the King was dead,
你说过 一旦国王逝去
you would choose one of these men to be your husband,
你会从这些先生们中选一位当丈夫
but you can't say which yet. Did you say that?
只是没确定是哪位 你是否说过这样的话
You must answer a loud.
你必须大声作出回答
No.
没有
Read me your charges.
说说你对我的指控
Put them to me, one by one.
一条一条的说
The places. The dates.
说出详细的地点 约会内容
I'll confound you!
我会辩的你狼狈不堪
Did you not affirm that you could never love the King in your heart?
你是否声明过 你永不会真心的爱国王
No.
没有
Did you not, at various times and places, by kissing, touchings,
你是否有在不同的时间 地点
and other infamous incitations,
通过亲吻 抚摸及身体接触
induce Francis Weston to be your concubine?
勾引弗朗西斯・威斯顿 使其成为你的姘夫
No.
没有
Did you not make gifts of money to Francis Weston?
你是否有给国弗朗西斯・威斯顿大笔金钱作为礼物
Yes.
有
Silence!
肃静
On this page are words the Queen is said to have spoken to you,
这张纸上记载了 据说是王后对你说过的话
and which, in turn, you passed on.
而你却散播了这些话语
Do not read them aloud.
不要念出声来
Just tell the court, do you recognise them?
就请告诉法庭 你是否记得这些话
"The King cannot copulate with a woman.
"国王无法与女人交媾
He has neither skill, nor vigour."
他既没技术 也没精力"
I didn't say...
这些话不是我说的...
These are not MY words.
这不是我要说的话
I don't own them!
不是我的原话
You do now.
可你刚刚已经说出口了
Having been found unanimously
经议会全员表决 现宣判被告
guilty...
有罪...
I'll do slaughter!
再不安静点就宰了你们
Thou shalt be burned here, within the Tower.
尔将被焚于伦敦塔内
Or else, to have thy head smitten off...
或 将尔之颅砍去
- ..as the King's pleasure... - That's not justice!
-...以显国王之大度... - 这不公平
- What are you talking about?  - What is it? What?
- 你们在说什么  - 怎么回事 怎么了?
These fellows say I've done it wrong.
这些家伙说我的判决有误
They say I have to say "burn" only...
他们说我只能说"焚"这个字...
The phrasing is the King's, and don't tell me
这本就是国王的原话
what we can or can't do, we've never tried a queen before.
也别跟我说哪些能做 哪些不能 这可是我们第一次审判王后
Finish what you're saying. Sit down.
继续把话说完 你们也坐下吧
..head smitten off,
...将颅砍去
as the King's pleasure shall be further known of this matter...
由此案 更可彰显国王之大度
Why does she keep looking up at the tower?
她为什么一直盯着塔顶看
Because she thinks there's still hope.
因为她觉得一切仍有希望
So, she will not be able to tell me from the other officials.
她没办法通过其他官员 告知我此事
It will save her alarm.
她很快会解脱的
Good, Christian people...
善良的基督教徒们...
..I am come hither to die.
..我是到此处来 是来受死的
For according to the law, and by the law, I am judged to die -
因为根据法律判决 我被判了死刑
I can't hear her.
我听不清她的话
You'd think she'd speak up for her last words.
你认为她是在说临终遗言吗
I am come hither to accuse no man...
我来此处 不为控诉任何人
..nor to speak any thing of that
..也不为我是因何种控诉
whereof I am accused and condemned to die.
如何判死刑 而辩解
But I pray God save the King...
但我祈祷上帝来拯救国王...
..and send him long to reign over you.
..并愿他长寿 让他的王位绵延万世
For a gentler nor a more merciful prince was there never.
因为从未有哪位王子 像他那般仁慈怜悯
And, to me, was he ever a good, a gentle and a sovereign lord.
于我而言 他是从未有过的 正直绅士的 至高无上的君主
And if any person will meddle of my cause, I require them to judge best.
若后人想评论我的所作所为 我希望他们能公正评判
And thus I take my leave of the world and of you all,
就这样 我将告别这世界 告别你们
and I heartily desire you all to pray for me.
我衷心希望你们能为我祈祷
Oh Lord, have mercy on my soul.
主啊 请宽恕我的灵魂
To God, I commend my soul.
上帝 我把灵魂交付于你
How will you do it?
你会怎样行刑
She kneels.
让她跪下
There is no block.
这样就毫无阻碍了
Christ have mercy, Jesus receive my soul...
基督 仁慈 耶稣 请收下我的灵魂...
If she is steady, it will be over in a moment.
如果她不乱动的话 一下子就完事
Between heartbeats. She knows nothing.
一瞬间的事 她甚至都不会有一点痛感的
IF...she is steady.
如果...她不乱动的话
Well, I can answer for her.
我可以确保 她不会乱动的
Put your arm down.
把你的手臂放下来
Apportez l'epee.
持剑而来 奉命而归
We do not want men to handle her.
我们不想让男人碰她的身体
It's a little late for that!
现在说这话 也太晚了哈 [暗指她乱交]
Right.
对了
I'm off to tell the Seymours it's done.
我要去告诉西摩家的人 一切都结束了
m -116 -16 l -102 -38 l -97 -38 l -109 -18 l -110 -19 l -110 -16 l -116 -16 m -96 -48 l -95 -41 l -100 -41 l -95 -48 m -85 -51 l -57 -51 l -57 -49 l -72 -49 l -72 -42 l -61 -42 l -61 -45 l -45 -45 l -43 -41 l -85 -41 l -85 -51 m -90 -30 l -99 -16 l -81 -16 l -90 -30 m -84 -38 l -60 -38 l -71 -34 l -71 -29 l -59 -34 l -56 -33 l -71 -26 l -71 -22 l -56 -28 l -56 -26 l -71 -20 l -71 -17 l -84 -38 m -50 -38 l -41 -38 l -39 -36 l -43 -36 l -45 -30 l -40 -16 l -47 -16 l -46 -18 l -46 -36 l -50 -38 m -36 -30 l -27 -16 l -31 -16 l -36 -30 m -56 -22 l -70 -16 l -61 -16 l -61 -18 l -56 -18 l -56 -22
彼以国士待我，我以国士待之，用过免费优质字幕服务， 而又有能力的人，有义务将这个免费服务做下去若有心加入我们 联系 QQ群 428872140 更多影视请搜索并关注新浪微博  @大家字幕组